When God speaks, reason can never
answer.
God cannot be sought at the level of
mind. God must be
experienced at the level of spirit. I
don't know who I'm preaching to right
now, but you keep telling God when he
shows you more,
you'll go more.
You keep telling God that you will obey
him once you understand the outcome. But
in matters of faith,
you know,
you have to
follow to find out. Abraham, go to a
land
I will show you. What's it going to be
like? You've got to
follow
to find out.
And you'll find out why I called you as
you follow.
I cannot describe to you what the next
season of your life will be like if you
follow God in faith. You will have to
follow
to find out.
And this is where most of us would have
never gotten past John chapter 1 verse
43. The whole thing would have ended
right there. Follow me, and we would
have waited for details, and he would
not have given them because Jesus
does not call you to figure out. He
calls you to follow.
And maybe that gives you relief because
there's a sense in which some of you in
your mind right now are trying to figure
everything out for the future of your
life and the next season of your life.
And maybe it can be an exhale for you or
a sigh of relief or a surrender to the
savior to know that he never called you
to figure out. He just called you to
follow.
But how are we going to pay for it?
Follow.
But how is it going to follow? But
what's going to happen in three follow.
We might not even be here in three
years. Have y'all watched the news? I
don't know about no three years. I'm
just following Jesus the best I can
today. Somebody asked me, "What's the
10-year plan for the church?" I'm doing
good to have a 10-minute plan for this
sermon. I don't even really know what
I'm going to say after this first point,
if you want to know the truth, but I'm
trying to follow. And as you follow, you
find out. That's what Philip knew. I've
got to find out. There was something in
Philip that said, "I want to find out."
I believe there's somebody in here who
God is calling you to follow him, and it
is unseasonably difficult for you to do
that right now. But don't you want to
find out what your life can be in his
hands?
Don't you want to find out how freedom
feels when you finally decide to forgive
that person?
Don't you want to find out what it feels
like to lay your head down on your
pillow at night knowing that you've
confessed your sin instead of continuing
to hide it? Don't you want to find out
what it's like to get beyond this
selfish me-first generation where I'm
simply just following the crowd, and I
say goodbye to the crowd, and I start
following the Christ who is greater than
the crowd? And something in Philip, I
can't prove it, but something in Philip,
I JUST INFERRED IT FROM the text, AND I
DEDUCED IT FROM WHAT IS WRITTEN, THAT HE
SAID, "I DON'T KNOW WHAT MY FUTURE IS,
BUT I want to find out behind this man."
You have to follow him
to find out.
So, sometimes
you have to see it
to believe it.
Here's what I want to talk about today.
Other times
you have to believe it
to see it.
You have to
believe it
to see it.
Now, these are the moments in life where
you have no physical proof
that what God spoke is true,
>> [snorts]
>> and it actually contradicts the way you
feel
in that moment. We're going to move on
from Philip for a moment, and we're
going to move to this character called
Nathanael. This is really who I wanted
to talk to you about today. I was just
telling you about Philip. Just in case
you can't figure out your life right
now, but God is calling you to follow
him anyway. That's probably not anybody
in here. You probably all got it figured
out, but some of us are still trying to
figure out what to do, and we don't know
what to do about this situation with an
aging parent or this situation with a
struggling child, and we don't know what
to do about this issue in our body, and
we're trying to figure it out, but God
is just calling us to follow. So, that
was for some of us. But, for the rest
of you
who have got it figured out, like like
Nathaniel, right? Nathaniel has got it
figured out.
Cuz Philip found Nathaniel and told him,
"We have found the one Moses wrote about
in the law." In other words, all of
these prophecies that were about Jesus.
And after meeting Jesus, he said,
"We found him.
And about whom the prophets also wrote,
Jesus
of Nazareth,
the son of Joseph."
We are seeking Jesus in this season of
our church.
And as we seek him, we need to pay
attention to everything we can learn
about him. And one of the things that we
need to learn from is the label that was
associated with him as he walked the
earth.
They didn't call him Jesus the savior
yet.
He hadn't died for them yet.
They did not call him Jesus the healer
yet because he hadn't performed any
miracles yet. Not yet.
They would see all of that as they
followed, but at this point they only
knew him this way. Watch. Jesus of
Nazareth. It was common to call somebody
by where they came from back then.
And then they call him the son of
Joseph. Well, that one's kind of
complicated, isn't it?
Cuz remember Mary's story, and she's
like, "I promise, Joseph, it was the
Holy Spirit."
He came from a questionable background.
So, when he called him Jesus of
Nazareth, watch Nathaniel's response.
And I was laughing at it as I read it.
And maybe you didn't know why. He said
verse 46,
Nazareth?
Can any Nath-
You said you found the Messiah?
And he comes from Nazareth? Yeah, that's
right, Nazareth. And then Nathanael
wants to know, can anything good come
from
there?
Come and see,
said Philip.
Now,
the reason that Nathanael had a negative
perspective of Nazareth is because it
was small and I studied this week.
Y'all, I studied so much this week. I
have no idea how I'm going to say amen
at the end of this sermon.
That's why I called the sermon begin
with amen. So, wherever we end, we'll
just end and come back next week. I
studied so much for this sermon. This is
how much I studied. I was waking up last
night every hour on the hour. 1:00 a.m.,
2:00 a.m., 3:00 a.m. At 4:00 a.m., I had
this horrible nightmare that on my way
to preach, I got in a terrible car
accident. I went to the hospital and I
was in the hospital, they had me all
hooked up, but I was trying to scan my
credit card to pay for the hospital
visit and I was telling them, I got to
go teach this series at the church. I
studied too much. That's how much I love
y'all. I was
I was my my
fictitious hospital bed, I got out of my
my my not really hospital bed to preach
this to you.
And I studied and found out that
Nathanael came
from somewhere near Nazareth, but not
Nazareth. Follow me.
Nathanael came from a place called Cana.
Cana was also in Galilee. But Cana was
north of Galilee.
Cana was distinguished. Cana was
sophisticated. Cana was a wealthy place.
Picture the part of town where you drive
through and judge the people and say, it
must be nice if I had all their money.
That was Cana.
Cana was a place where if you came from
there, you wore the sweat shirt.
Straight out of Cana, you would not feel
like you came out of the mud. You would
feel like you came from privilege. And
so, I'm not calling Nathaniel a snob.
I'm just saying that he looked down on
where Jesus came from. So, when he says,
"Can anything good come from there?"
Come and see, he's giving a negative
interpretation of where Jesus came from
based on his background. He believes a
certain thing about a certain place. And
because he believes a certain thing
about a certain place, he cannot accept
a certain person that came from a
certain place. Only problem is John
chapter 1 verse 1. John chapter 1 verse
1 says, "In the beginning was the word,
and the word was with God, and the word
was God. He was with God in the
beginning. Uh through him all things
were made. Through him, Jesus, all
things were made. Without him, nothing
was made that has been made." And the
Lord stopped me and showed me something
that Nathaniel thought that Jesus came
from Nazareth. But Jesus didn't really
come from Nazareth.
If John chapter 1 verse 1 through 3 is
correct, and through Jesus everything
was made that was made, that means Jesus
didn't come from Nazareth. Nazareth came
from Jesus. And I CAME TO PREACH ABOUT
JESUS TODAY. OH, I PREACHED THAT BETTER
THAN Y'ALL RESPONDED. THROUGH HIM ALL
THINGS WERE CREATED. HE IS NOT SUBJECT
TO WHAT he made. HE IS NOT SUBJECT TO A
HUMAN LABEL. He is not a baby that was
born in a barn. HE IS THE PRE-EXISTING
GOD WHO IN JOHN CHAPTER 1 VERSE 14
BECAME FLESH. THAT'S INCARNATION AND
DWELT AMONG US and we beheld HIS GLORY,
THE GLORY AS OF THE one who came from
the Father. So, they said he came from
Nazareth. He said he came FROM THE
FATHER. THEY SAID HE CAME FROM A SMALL
PLACE. HE SAID I CAME FROM A PLACE THAT
YOU'VE NEVER SEEN BECAUSE IN THE
BEGINNING WAS THE WORD AND THE WORD WAS
WITH GOD AND THE WORD WAS GOD AND
NOTHING EXISTS without him and so all
I'm saying is God is bigger than your
background.
God is bigger than your background.
Ooh, God is bigger than what you think
about him. God is bigger than your
little tradition about him. God is
bigger than what you were taught about
him. God will come to places that you
were taught he'd stay away from. God
will use people that you taught you were
taught he hated. God will do things that
you were taught were impossible. GOD
WILL DO THINGS NOW, I'M NOT SAYING I'VE
seen all of it, but sometimes
you have to believe it
to see it.
So, if the enemy can keep you from
believing it
because you've never seen it
he can keep you from ever seeing it and
experiencing it.
And he can keep you
from seeing it if he can keep you
from believing it.
Wow.
>> [applause]
>> Not Nazareth.
Nothing good can come from Nazareth.
Somebody say not Nazareth.
Now, for Nazareth just put whatever in
the blank you don't think God can use.
Not heartbreak.
Not Nazareth. No, no, no. Nothing good
can come from a broken heart.
The Bible says a broken and a contrite
heart he will not despise.
He will dwell
in what you despise. Not Nazareth.
I know you didn't want to get a divorce
and now you're saying, "Not after a
divorce, God can't use me."
I got a word for you.
Follow him and find out.
>> [applause]
>> One man said, "Fool around and find
out." But this is the church version.
Follow him and find out.
I don't care what they called you. I
don't care what they said about you. I'm
going to come over on this side. I
always come down that wrong side of the
steps. God is looking for somebody today
who will follow him and find out. No,
God can't use me. I'm an alcoholic.
Follow him and find out. What if God
gives you that same passion for his
presence that you used to have for a
substance? Follow him and find out. I
speak to somebody who's a drug dealer
right now. You're about to be a disciple
and you're about to turn the chain of
supply and demand on his head.
Cuz when you get hooked into this vine,
there's an unlimited supply. And I don't
care what they said about you. And I
don't care what you've said about
yourself.
>> [music]
>> I don't even know what you've been
labeling your kids. I don't even KNOW
WHAT THE DOCTOR TOLD YOU TUESDAY. BUT
FOLLOW HIM AND FIND OUT. HE'S A HEALER.
HE'S A WAY MAKER. HE'S A CHAIN BREAKER.
HE'S A STONE ROLLER. YES, HE IS.
AND HE CAME FROM NAZARETH.
SO, IF YOU'RE GOING TO SEEK JESUS, YOU
MIGHT HAVE TO LOOK IN NAZARETH. YOU
MIGHT HAVE TO LOOK IN A DIRTY PLACE. YOU
MIGHT HAVE TO GET HONEST about what
YOU'RE GOING THROUGH. YOU MIGHT HAVE TO
GET AUTHENTIC AND QUIT PRETENDING LIKE
you have IT TOGETHER AND STOP SAYING,
"PRAISE THE LORD, WE'RE FINE, AND PICK
UP THE PHONE AND CALL A COUNSELOR AND
SAY I NEED HELP CUZ THE HELP MIGHT COME
FROM NAZARETH.
>> [applause]
>> Nazareth
Nazareth
Nazareth. I kept saying it wrong all
week. Na Nazareth. Like I was saying
Lazarus and Nazareth. And the Lord said,
"Well, what do the two things have in
common?" I said, "Both were situations
where everybody thought it was over."
And both were places where God displayed
his glory.
You better follow him and find out.
Ooh, ooh, ooh, ooh. I know when the Lord
speaking, I'm not moving. I am not
moving to my next point. It would be a
shame
for you to let the shame
of where you came from
stop you from seeing the glory of who
you came from.
>> [applause]
>> I got to show them verse 4, babe.
I got to show them verse 4 verse 14
says, "The word became flesh
and made his dwelling among us, and we
have seen
his glory,
the glory of the one and only son, who
came
from the Father. Can anything good come
from Nazareth? Nazareth? Na Nazareth?
Lazarus? Na Na Can anything good come
from that?"
Well,
it depends because before he came from
Nazareth,
he came from the Father.
Everything that God allowed to happen in
your life passed through his hands.
And it has to go back through his hands.
And we
have seen
his glory. Now,
they say you have to see it to believe
it, but back up to verse 12. John
chapter 1 verse 12.
Yet to all who did receive him, to those
who believed in his name,
he gave the right to become children of
God.
See it?
Circle the word believed, Justin.
Believed
in his name.
Verse 14 again.
And the word became flesh, that's Jesus,
and made his dwelling among us. We have
seen
his glory.
Circle the word seen.
Sometimes you have to see it to believe
it, I get that.
But sometimes you have to believe it
to see it.
See, if I don't believe
that God is my provider,
I won't see the provision.
You get it? It's a complete inversion.
That's why Jesus' kingdom is upside
down, but it's actually right side up,
cuz it's a complete inversion. The
Gospel of John is not just about
miracles. The Gospel of John is not just
happy meals being fed to a crowd of
5,000. The Gospel of John is not just
water walking and storms. The Gospel of
John is not just unique conversations.
The Gospel of John is themed around
belief, belief in the Son of God, belief
in Jesus, not just what he did, but who
he is. It is the theme of the Gospel.
Believe, believe, believe. And he said
to those who believe, you see the glory.
So, when you believe God is a provider,
it opens your eyes to see provision that
you were walking past just the day
before.
And if I remind you today that he's a
provider, and if I force you by faith to
follow him and find out in your next
step of your life, you may see that he
has already made the plan to provide for
the thing that you're praying about.
And he may have already worked out the
situation that you are so worried about.
And I have found it to be true that if I
do not believe that he's my provider,
I won't see the provision.
Old Testament example, let's do this
class real quick. In 2 Kings 4, a woman
came to Elisha, he was the prophet,
said, "My husband is dead. I need you to
help. I need you to provide for me." The
prophet said back, "What do you have in
your house? How can I help you?" She
said, "Nothing
except
a jar
of oil.
What happened?
The moment that she believed, because
the prophet said you have something in
your house, she could see what she was
unable to see before she believed.
So, when I believe that God is my
provider, it opens my mind and opens my
eyes to begin to consider some of the
things that he's given me in my life
that may be in seed form right now, but
just because it's a seed doesn't mean
it's not supply.
Hey, thanks for stopping by my YouTube
channel. I hope you were blessed today.
[music] If you were, share this with
somebody. Like and subscribe and leave
me a comment. [music]
Let me know where you're watching from,
what we can pray for you about. Hope to
see you back here again really soon.